utcfireandsecurity.com 2014-06-25

# Privacy

**Intro**  

This Privacy Statement covers how United Technologies Corporation's subsidiaries and affiliates that operate under the UTC Building & Industrial Systems reporting unit (“BIS”) collect and treat information received via their websites, webpages, and mobile applications (Sites). At BIS we believe that, as our online visitor, you have a right to know our practices regarding the information we collect when you visit our Sites, including the type of information that is collected and how we use it. The guidelines contained herein only apply to your visit to this site, but does not include any redirect URLs that link the user to another internet domain.

**Information Collection and Use**  

Some portions of the Site may request that a user complete a registration form. We send users who register themselves or their products via our Sites a welcoming email to confirm their registration. Registered customers may elect to receive information on products, services, announcements and special offers. Out of respect for the privacy of our users we present the option to not receive these types of communications. Users who have provided personal information on our Sites that have not opted out of receiving these communications may occasionally be contacted with product offers if they have elected to receive this information. We also may communicate with a user to provide requested services with regards to issues relating to the user's requests, via email or phone. Users that wish to update their information may do so as explained in the “How to Contact Us or Update Your Information” section below.

A user may also have the option to register their products via the Site (product registration). Depending on which product is being registered, a user may be required to give their contact information such as name, address, email address, company name, company address, phone number, the model and serial number of the product being registered, and computer system information, such as operating system type, operating system version, and operating system language. The information required is related to the product being registered and information needed to communicate with you. BIS uses this information to provide you with enhanced levels of technical support and, unless you opt out of receiving these communications, to alert you to product updates, special offers, promotions and updated information regarding new services or programs available from BIS. BIS may request and collect optional demographic information.

A user may have the option to submit a question or concern via the Site using a customer service/contact form. The user is required to provide their name, email address, and contact information so that we can answer their question or request. Also, the customer service/contact form may be routed to our third party service provider, who assists BIS in answering customer requests from our Sites.

You may also be able to send certain content to your friends. If applicable to do so, we ask you to provide your name and your friend's email address. We use this information to send the content to your friend.

A user may have the option to request that BIS contact them regarding how to become a dealer. The user is required to provide their name, email address and other contact information so that we can respond to their request.

Site registration, product registration, becoming a dealer, and customer service/contact form information is collected by BIS. An automatic email confirmation is sent to the user when they submit any of these forms.

If you email us through the “Contact Us” link on this Site, we ask you for information such as your name and email address so we can respond to your questions and comments. You may choose to provide additional information that we request as well.

BIS may use any of the information it collects to create and publish website or application content most relevant to you, as well as for the other purposes described above.

**Disclosures of your Information**

Except as explained in the “Business Transitions” section below, we will not disclose the information we collect to anyone except BIS personnel or our third party providers who need the information for customer service purposes, such as responding to a request for assistance or information, or that otherwise provide services to us, such as shippers and suppliers. Except as explained in the “Business Transitions” section below, we will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information to other third parties without first obtaining your consent, except when required by law.

In addition, BIS may use or disclose personal information we have collected in the good faith belief that BIS is lawfully authorized to do so, or that doing so is reasonably necessary to protect you, to comply with legal process or authorities, to respond to any claims, or to protect the rights, property or personal safety of BIS, our customers, our employees or the public.

**Business Transitions**  
In the event that one of BIS' subsidiaries or affiliates goes through a business transition, such as a merger, divestment, acquisition, reorganization, restructuring, or other similar type of transaction, we may transfer your personal information along with other transferred assets.

**Cookies**  
Like many companies, we use browser cookies on this website. Browser cookies are bits of text that are placed on your computer's hard drive when you visit certain websites. We use browser cookies to tell us, for example, whether you have visited us before or if you are a new visitor and to help us identify site features in which you may have the greatest interest. Browser cookies may enhance your online experience by saving your preferences while you are visiting a particular website. The “help” portion of the toolbar on most browsers will tell you how to stop accepting new browser cookies, how to be notified when you receive a new browser cookie, and how to disable existing browser cookies. Remember though, without browser cookies, you may not be able to take full advantage of all our website features. 

For each visitor to a BIS Site, BIS's web server automatically recognizes and stores information, such as the visitor's IP address/domain name combination and any referring websites. We use this information to understand visitor traffic patterns through our websites for purposes such as enhancing their usability. Your computer provides this information automatically each time you log on, unless you have activated blocking technology available in some browsers. 

Some newer browsers have incorporated “Do Not Track” features. Most of these features, when turned on, send a signal or preference to the web sites you visit indicating that you do not wish to be tracked. Those sites (or the third party content on those sites) may continue to engage in activities you might view as tracking even though you have expressed this preference, depending on the sites' privacy practices. If your browser or similar mechanism gives our Site a “do not track” signal, the Site may not honor it because of the tracking described in this section (“Approved Sharing”). If your settings and our Site are nuanced enough to allow the Approved Sharing but also preclude tracking for behavioral advertising by third parties, the Site will make commercially reasonable attempts to honor your settings. However, BIS provides no warrants or guaranties about the effects of any opt-out choice that you make because of things such as this: (a) such nuanced treatment isn't necessarily available or effective for any or all browsers, mechanisms or technologies and our attempts might or might not be effective to preclude tracking at all or over any particular period of time; (b) not all third parties will necessarily honor our attempts; (c) BIS does not control third parties or technologies (even if we have a contract), and (d) technologies used by you and third parties will change from time to time and our attempts might or might not be effective for each technology.  

** **  
 **Web Beacons**  
We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. Certain pages on our site may contain “web beacons” (also known as Internet tags, pixel tags and clear GIFs). These web beacons allow third parties to obtain information such as the IP address of the computer that downloaded the page on which the beacon appears, the URL of the page on which the beacon appears, the time the page containing the beacon was viewed, the type of browser used to view the page, and the information in cookies set by the third party. We use log files to store the data that is collected through web beacons. BIS also uses third party web beacons to help manage online advertising. These web beacons are provided by our ad management partners, such as Google Analytics and Omniture. These files enable Google Analytics and Omniture to recognize a unique cookie on your web browser, which in turn enables us to learn which advertisements bring users to our website. The cookie on your web browser was placed by BIS, or by another advertiser who works with Google Analytics. With both cookies and web beacon technology, the information that we collect and share is anonymous and not personally identifiable. It does not contain your name, address, telephone number or email address. For more information about Google Analytics, including information about how to opt out of these technologies, go to [www.google-analytics.com](http://www.google-analytics.com/). For more information about Omniture, including how to opt out of these technologies, go to [www.omniture.com](http://www.omniture.com/). 

**Security**  
BIS takes reasonable security precautions to protect our subscribers' personally identifiable information that we collect on the Sites from unauthorized access, use, and disclosure. However, BIS cannot guarantee that our security precautions will prevent every unauthorized attempt to access, use, or disclose your personally identifiable information.

**Sharing**  
We will share aggregated demographic information with our partners. This is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. We do not sell or otherwise disclose personal information about our Site users, without their prior authorization. We may share information provided by our users with service providers we have retained to perform services on our behalf. These service providers are contractually restricted from using or disclosing the information except as necessary to perform services on our behalf or to comply with legal requirements. In addition, we may disclose information about you (i) if we are required to do so by law or legal process, (ii) to law enforcement authorities or other government officials, or (iii) when we believe disclosure is necessary or appropriate to prevent physical harm or financial loss or in connection with an investigation of suspected or actual illegal activity. We reserve the right to transfer any information we have about you in the event we sell or transfer all or a portion of our business or assets. Should such a sale or transfer occur, we will use reasonable efforts to direct the transferee to use the personal information you have provided through the Sites in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Statement.

**  **  
**Links**  

Our Sites may contain links to other websites. Please be aware that BIS is not responsible for the privacy practices of third party websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site and to read the privacy policies of any website you visit that may collect personally identifiable information.

**Surveys**  

We occasionally may ask visitors to our Sites to complete online surveys and opinion polls about their activities, attitudes and interests. These surveys help us serve you better and improve the usefulness of our Sites. In conducting these surveys we may collect personal information such as your name and email address or demographic information such as zip code or age level. We do not keep any personal information about you in connection with your participation in a survey unless you specifically agree to provide that information.

**Supplementation of Information**  

We collect certain aggregate and non-personal information when you visit the Sites. Aggregate and non-personal information does not relate to a single identifiable visitor or user. It tells us such things as how many users visited our site and the pages accessed. By collecting this information, we learn how to best tailor our Sites to our visitors and users. We collect this information either through “cookie” technology or with “web beacons,” as explained above.

**Notification of Changes**  

This Privacy Statement may be updated periodically and without prior notice to you to reflect changes in our online information practices. We will post a prominent notice on the Site to notify you of any significant changes to our Privacy Statement and indicate at the top of the statement when it was most recently updated. Changes to this Privacy Statement are effective at the time they are posted to the Site, and your continued use of the Site after posting will constitute acceptance of, and agreement to be bound by, those changes.

**Transfer of Info to Foreign Countries**  

We may transfer the personal information we collect on the Site to other countries where we do business, but we will do so only for the purposes described above. When we transfer your information to other countries, we will protect that information as described here unless otherwise required by applicable laws. In particular, customers, suppliers and service providers doing business with some of BIS' European affiliates should be aware such BIS affiliates transfer various types of customer, supplier and service provider information (which includes your, and possibly certain of your employees', personal information) from the European Economic Area to the United States for electronic storage, processing and use by its American affiliates, in connection with and in furtherance of the BIS' business and its relationships with their customers, suppliers and service providers. In particular, this information transfer is made in order to facilitate BIS sales and delivery of goods and services to its customers and to facilitate collection and receipt of payment for those goods and services, to facilitate BIS' purchases of goods and services from its suppliers and service providers and to facilitate payment for those goods and services, as well as to assist in performing any agreements with customers, suppliers and service providers, internal training, the prevention of abuse, fraud, money laundering or terrorism financing.

**Consent to Processing  **  

By providing any personal information to the BIS Sites, all users, including without limitation users in the member states of the European Union, fully understand and unambiguously consent to the collection and processing of such information in the United States of America.

**Children's Privacy  **  

The Site is not directed to children under the age of thirteen and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of thirteen on the Sites. If we become aware that we have inadvertently received personal information from a visitor under the age of thirteen on the Site, we will delete the information from our records.

**How to Contact Us  **  

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Statement or if you would like us to update information we have about you or your preferences, please contact us by writing us at:

UTC Building & Industrial Systems  
One Carrier Place  
Farmington, CT 06032

_Last updated by the BIS Intellectual Property Department on December 16, 2013_

___Copyright © United Technologies Corporation 2013. All rights reserved._
